#### Contact

9402328698 (Mobile) rupert.laco@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rupertlaco (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Healthcare

Nursing

**Patient Safety** 

#### Languages

English (Full Professional)

Tagalog (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Basic Life Support for Healthcare Providers (BLS)

Nurse Executive-Board Certified Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support Instructor

Pediatric Advanced Life Support

Certified Professional in Healthcare Quality

#### Honors-Awards

American Nurses Association/ California Florence Nightingale Award

60th Inpatient Operations Squadron Junior Company Grade Officer of the Year

60th Medical Group Junior Company Grade Officer of the Year

University of South Alabama College of Nursing Leadership Award

Air Force Sergeants Association Chapter 652 Airman of the Year

# Rupert "Energizer" Laco

MSN, RN, CMSRN, TCRN, RN-BC, NE-BC, NHDP-BC, CPHQ US Military Posts in the Pacific

# Summary

To excellently serve as a United States Air Force Nurse Corps Officer with healthcare leadership, clinical knowledge, and performance improvement expertise. I will lead our Airmen and accomplish executive tasks with flexibility and integrity. I am devoted to upholding military standards and principles of care. I will place our Airmen first. I am committed to their lifelong professional development through coaching, mentoring, and relationship building. I worked and communicated successfully, efficiently, and professionally with others. I am passionate about our Air Force traditions (Integrity, Service, Excellence), nursing, and health advancement of our patients.

# Experience

United States Air Force 13 years 4 months

Emergency Services Flight Commander (Nurse Manager) April 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)

374th Medical Group, Yokota Air Base, Japan

Emergency Services Flight Commander (Nurse Manager) at the 374th Medical Group, Yokota Air Base, Japan (Small MTF)

Urgent Care Element Chief (Assistant Nurse Manager) January 2017 - April 2019 (2 years 4 months) 374th Medical Group, Yokota Air Base, Japan

Urgent Care Element Chief (Assistant Nurse Manager) at the 374th Medical Group, Yokota Air Base, Japan (Small MTF)

Clinical Nurse, Urgent Care Clinic October 2016 - January 2017 (4 months)

374th Medical Group, Yokota Air Base, Japan

Clinical Nurse, Urgent Care Clinic at the 374th Medical Group, Yokota Air Base, Japan (Small MTF)

Medical Inpatient Element Chief (Assistant Nurse Manager)
April 2016 - October 2016 (7 months)

David Grant USAF Medical Center, Travis Air Force Base, California

Medical Inpatient Element Chief (Assistant Nurse Manager) at David Grant USAF Medical Center, Travis Air Force Base, California (Large MTF)

Clinical Nurse, Charge Nurse, & Supervisor, Medical Inpatient Flight August 2012 - April 2016 (3 years 9 months)

David Grant USAF Medical Center, Travis Air Force Base, California

Clinical Nurse, Charge Nurse, & Supervisor, Medical Inpatient Flight at David Grant USAF Medical Center, Travis Air Force Base, California (Large MTF)

Officer Trainee (Undergraduate Student), AFROTC Detachment 014 August 2010 - August 2012 (2 years 1 month)

Mobile, Alabama Area

Officer Trainee (Undergraduate Student) at AFROTC Detachment 014

Aerospace Med Service Specialist (EMT & Nursing Assistant) & Shift Leader, Medical Inpatient Flight

March 2007 - August 2010 (3 years 6 months)

Keesler Medical Center, Keesler Air Force Base, Mississippi

Aerospace Med Service Specialist (EMT & Nursing Assistant) & Shift Leader, Medical Inpatient Flight at Keesler Medical Center, Keesler Air Force Base, Mississippi (Large MTF)

Aerospace Med Service Specialist (EMT & Nursing Assistant), Contingency Aeromedical Staging Flight August 2009 - January 2010 (6 months)

86th Medical Group, Ramstein Air Base, Germany

Aerospace Medical Service Specialist (EMT & Nursing Assistant), Contingency Aeromedical Staging Flight (OPERATION ENDURING FREEDOM/ OPERATION IRAQI FREEDOM), 86th Medical Group, Ramstein Air Base, Germany

# Education

University of South Alabama

Doctor of Nursing Practice, Executive Nursing Administration · (2019 - 2020)

University of South Alabama

Master of Science in Nursing, Executive Nursing Administration · (2013 - 2016)

University of South Alabama

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Nursing · (2010 - 2012)

Community College of the Air Force
Associate of Applied Science, Allied Health · (2007 - 2009)

University of Perpetual Help System DALTA Associate, Health Science Education · (2004 - 2006)